# **Victor Matthews**

**Q** Denver, Colorado
 ■ victormmatthews@gmail.com
 □ (616) 970 0690
 in/victor-matthews-x
 ■ https://victormmatthews.me

## **SUMMARY**

Experienced software engineer with a demonstrated history of working in supply chain management of the food & beverages industry and a focus on inventory control and material handling control systems. Skilled in Java, Angular, and SQL. Strong engineering professional, graduated from Ferris State University.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Associate Software Engineer**

Gordon Food Service | IT Warehouse Team

March 2016 - Present, Grand Rapids, MI

- · Working with the IT Warehouse team, I have helped develop and support the warehouse management system.
- · Subject matter expert on Inventory Control and Material Handling Control Systems.
- $\cdot$  On a team of 14 people I played a big part in the most recent warehouse project where we created and deployed a new Angular app to replace old telnet devices in the warehouses.
- · Updated and revamped software used throughout the entire warehouse for receiving, selection, inventory control, and shipping.
- · Completed 22% of the 200+ bugs that came in over the 10 month roll-out of the software to all warehouses.

#### **Asset Administrator**

Gordon Food Service (North American Asset Management Team)

May 2015 - March 2016, Grand Rapids, MI

- · Automated the internal IT hardware & software PO request system using JavaScript, resulting in faster throughput for PO requests.
- · Awarded the Gordon Food Service J&P Cup award, a yearly award given to one of the IT teams.
- · Implemented field validation for forms to make sure the user had all the information needed, based on their specific requests.
- · Added the ability for an Asset Administrator on the team to generate a PO number, save as a PDF, and store the request in the proper folder with a click of a button.

#### Sales Associate

**Gordon Food Service** 

September 2013 - May 2015, Grand Rapids, MI

- · Working at a Gordon Food Service Retail Store in Grand Rapids, MI.
- · I showed my work ethic and made connections that eventually got me a position in the corporate office as a Software Engineer more than a year before getting my degree.

# **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Science in Digital Media Software Engineering

Ferris State University · Grand Rapids, MI · 2017

### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

# 5x Ferris State University College of Education & Human Services Dean's List of Scholars | 2014 - 2017

 $\cdot$  Awarded honor roll due to high academic achievement

### Gordon Food Service J&P Cup Winner | 2015 | North American Asset Management Team

 $\cdot$  Awarded for work detailed in my role as an Asset Administrator with Gordon Food Service, automating and increasing throughput of PO Requests.

## **SKILLS**

Back End: Java, SQL, C#

Front End: Angular 2+, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Misc: Git, Node.js, REST, Spring, Maven